Andrew Boardman

Briefly

Designer and studio founder with 20 years of experience in graphic design, digital strategy and visual production. Grew up in Philadelphia, worked and studied in New York, moved with family to Winnipeg in 2005. Student of design history, social entrepreneurship and critical theory. Developing first book (design and responsibility). Avid runner, ardent environmentalist, practicing artist, guitar novice.

Experience

Manoverboard Inc.

Principal

2002-present

Lead and manage purpose-driven graphic design firm that is the first Certified B Corporation in Manitoba. Corporate mission is to help organizations create a better world by design. Create and build customized websites, reports, and brand identities. Recipient of numerous design awards. Clients have included Greyston, Barneys New York, EQ3, University of Manitoba, Ducks Unlimited and Acumen.

Red River College

Instructor

2017-2018

Taught design history and design management to first- and second-year students. Revamped course curricula to advance collaboration and critical thinking.

GDC Manitoba

President

2015-2018

Managed chapter of approximately 75 graphic designers. Work directly with very active, volunteer board to bring design events, workshops, and mentorship to Winnipeg design community. Served on board for ten consecutive years.

Oven Digital

Director of Research

2000-2002

Directed design and technology research for large digital agency in New York City. Clients included Tiffany & Co., MoMA, Consumer Reports, Kodak, IBM, The City of New York. Produced white papers and reports for client and corporate use.

The Rockefeller Foundation

Research Associate

1996-2000

Led research and development for large national fellowship program promoting civil society. Worked directly with fellows across U.S. to build leadership skills and organizational capacity. Developed curricula and facilitated workshops.

Education

Brown University

Providence, RI

1985-1989

B.A. magna cum laude, Honors Visual Art and Honors English, Phi Beta Kappa

University at Albany, SUNY

Albany, NY

1990-1992

M.F.A. with Honors, graduate assistant fellowship

Fulbright Fellowship

Krakow, Poland

1994-1995

Post-graduate study at Akademia Sztuk Pięknych (Academy of Fine Arts)

New School for Social Research New York, NY

1998-1999

Certificate in Media Management with focus on online entrepreneurship

343 Bartlet Avenue Winnipeg, MB R3L 0Z9

204-509-9327 andrew@manoverboard.com